

Daniel J Carlson

LINKS AND PROJECTS

dcrlsn610@gmail.com

Portfolio

GitHub

LinkedIn

https://allmylinks.com/dcrlsn610

WEB DEVELOPMENT

HTML, CSS, JavaScript **REST APIs** MERN Stack (MongoDB Express.js React.js Node.js) iQuery Redis OAuth Responsive Design Bootstrap Firebase Cookies Local Storage MvSOL NoSQL Apache NGINX Security and Session Storage

TOOLS

User Authentication

AWS
Hyper-V
VMWare
Docker
Kubernetes, Rancher
Microsoft Domain Services
(365 Suite, AD, SCCM, GPO)
Linux Debian SUSE RHEL
CentOS KALI Alpine Slax
Adobe Creative Cloud Suite
Fusion360, Solidworks
Nmap, Procmon

4939 Central Ave Charlotte, NC 28205 (484) 893-0943 Passionate and dedicated IT professional, with 10+ years of experience helping small business and individuals adapt with new technologies and scale their reach and businesses. Easily able to adapt to new environments and frameworks. Great at breaking down projects into smaller components and time management. Amazing technical communicator who can explain complex concepts in easy to understand ways. Not intimidated by new technologies and frameworks and rapidly adapting to them.

EXPERIENCE

A to PC, Lehigh Valley, PA — Owner

January 2016 to October 2021

Continued the work from Symmetric Systems Solutions as well as worked with nonprofits. Implemented and managed cloud based services such as Office365, Azure, and AWS for data backups and accessibility. As well as onboarding and offboarding users. Planned and installed audio equipment, video equipment, and streaming services to increase outreach for nonprofits.

Symmetric Systems Solutions, Lehigh Valley, PA

August 2009 to October 2015

Provided On-Demand IT services to small businesses and individuals, implemented and supported project-specific software solutions for home and small business, uprooted services through online media, company website, and advertisements, provided graphics and web design/hosting services. Planned, built, and installed custom networked systems to meet client needs

EDUCATION

University of North Carolina at Charlotte, NC

2021 to 2022

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

Northampton Community College, Lehigh Valley, PA

2007 to 2009

Studied Computer Science Networking